Rose Sherwood / Gladys Wells Papers
Rose Sherwood / Gladys Wells Papers
1896-1961
Sherwood, Rose L.; Wells, Gladys S.
2.0 linear feet
Correspondence, 1896-1961; travel journals, 1920, 1924-1932; and writings of Rose L. Sherwood. Inscribed books, memorabilia, teaching materials, and writings of Gladys S. Wells, 1948-1961.
148665
Biographical History
Little is known of Rose L. Sherwood or her daughter Gladys S. [Sherwood?] Wells other than what can be gleaned from the collection. Rose evidently enjoyed the theater and wrote articles for Broadway Magazine. According to her daughter, she was a pioneer woman insurance executive. Gladys may have been a teacher of English and was clearly interested in Japan and Japanese culture. Both women traveled to Europe and Gladys went to Japan.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Rose Sherwood / Gladys Wells Papers consists of the papers of two women, Rose L. Sherwood and Gladys S. [Sherwood?] Wells.
Rose L. Sherwood's papers contain correspondence, two travel diaries (one of a California trip, the other of "European travels"), memorabilia, and writings (two articles published in Broadway Magazine).
Gladys S. Wells' papers include published books by others, both fiction and non-fiction; memorabilia, most related to a trip to Japan; teaching materials, including some on teaching English to Spanish-Americans; a research paper by Wells on well-known author Lafcadio Hearn; and assorted memorabilia, including some relating to conferences and conventions.
Arrangement of the Collection
Material is arranged alphabetically by topic.
Subject and Genre Headings
Women Authors; Hearn, Lafcadio, 1850-1904.; Sherwood, Rose L.; Wells, Gladys S.; English language -- Study and teaching -- Foreign speakers.; California -- Description and travel.; Europe -- Description and travel.; Japan -- Description and travel.; Articles.; Correspondence.; Diaries.; Memorabilia.; Photographs.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Sherwood, Rose L.
  - Correspondence
    - General, 1896-1897; 1923-1961; 4 folders (Box 1)
    - Insurance-related, 1932-1961 (Box 1)
  - Diaries
    - California trip, 1920 (Box 1)
    - European travels, 1924-1932 (Box 1)
  - Memorabilia
    - Plaque honoring membership in The Equitable Veteran Legion, 1955 (Box 1)
    - Scrapbook, 1923-1946 (Box 1)
    - Theater programs, 1951-1964; undated (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous items, 1896-1937 (Box 1)
  - Writings
    - "Hello, beautiful" in Broadway Magazine, p. 24, 30 May 1931 (Box 1)
    - "The little side room" in Broadway Magazine, p. 44, 11 Apr 1931 (Box 1)
- Wells, Gladys
  - Books
    - Alger, Horatio. Tom the bootblack, or A western boy's success. New York, The New York Book Company, 1909 (Box 1)
    - Apton, Adolph Abraham. Your mind and appearance. New York, Citadel Press, 1951; inscribed by the author to Mrs. Jutta Fist, and by Mrs. Fist to Gladys Wells (Box 1)
    - Caprio, Frank. Helping yourself with psychiatry. Englewood Cliffs, New Jersey, Prentice-Hall, 1957; inscribed by the author to Gladys Wells (Box 2)
    - Greenough, William C. and Francis P. King. Retirement and insurance plans in American colleges. New York, Columbia University Press, 1959 (Box 2)
    - Lawing, Nellie Neal. Alaska Nellie. [Seattle?], Chieftain Press, inscribed by "Alaske Nellie" to Gladys Wells (Box 2)
    - [New South Wales]. New South Wales, Australia. [Sydney?], 1959? (Box 2)
    - Roosevelt, Eleanor. This is my story New York, Bantam Books, 1950; paperback; inscribed by the author to Gladys Wells (Box 2)
    - Tugwell, Rexford G. The art of politics, as practiced by three great American: Franklin Delano Roosevelt, Luis Munoz Marin, and Fiorello H. La Guardia. Garden City, N.Y., Doubleday, 1958; inscribed by the author (Box 2)
  - Memorabilia
    - Photocopies of miscellaneous items (Box 2)
    - Photograph albums
      - Japan trip, 1948-1949 (Box 2)
      - Japan (mostly Utsonomiya), 1949 (Box 2)
      - "A photograph report of occupied Japan" by Gladys S. Wells, 1948-1949; 1951 (Oversize 1)
    - Postcard album of Japan trip (Box 3)
    - Scrapbook of Japan trip, 1948-1949; 1955 (Box 3)
    - Souvenirs, 1948 (Box 3)
  - Miscellanea
    - Convention and conference programs, 1957-1960 (Box 3)
    - France-related periodicals
      - La Boheme, cahiers 13-15, 1963-1964 (Box 2)
      - French News, Jan 1961 (Box 2)
      - The French Review, 6 issues, May 1963-May 1964 (Box 2)
    - Japanese calendar art, 1962 (Oversize 2)
    - Newspaper obituaries, photocopies, 1951; undated (Box 3)
    - Published material, 1932-1963; includes single numbers of periodicals and an exhibition catalog (Box 4)
  - Teaching materials
    - Asia, printed material; 3 folders (Box 4)
    - Speech and reading, printed material (Box 4)
    - Teaching of English to Spanish-Americans, printed material (Box 4)
    - Yugoslavia, printed material (Box 4)
  - Writings
    - "The human cricket and the phantom past", 1961; research paper on Lafcadio Hearn (Box 4)